Something comes to mind from my own experience,
说到家庭
when we talk about family.
我想起了些个人经验
I grew up happily in a particular family,
我在一个特定的家庭里开心地长大
but around time I turned thirteen,
但当我快13岁时候
[I] became … And maybe, this is common—
这可能很常见
the onset of puberty, etc.
青春期的少年
To start questioning and examining everything.
开始质疑询问周围的一切
[Who am I?]
我是谁？
But one day, in the kitchen …
但有一天，在厨房
My mother is there, talking to me, like, washing and talking.
我母亲边洗盘子边跟我讲话
I’m sitting at the table, eating something.
我坐在桌边吃着东西
And suddenly it occurred to me, and I said,
这时突然冒出来个想法
Like I’m very known to her.
非常了解我
And I am assuming that I know her very well.
我认为我对她也很了解
And she is intimately known to me.”
我们关系很密切。”
But then I thought, “I don’t think I’ve clearly focused
但之后我想了
on my mother’s face for a very long time”,
“我很久没有认真地看着她的脸”
’cause your mother’s just always part of the environment.
因为一般母亲都变成了背景图
So since these strange feelings came to me,
自从有了这些奇怪的想法
I waited, when she came …
当她走过来
She’s just going on, talking about this, that, the other things …
继续说这说那
But then when she came and looked at me …
来到我面前看着我
I looked at, I started scrutinizing her face,
我开始仔细地盯着她的脸
and for a few moments I couldn’t recognize, who she was.
瞬间我无法辨认她到底是谁
And I thought, “This is totally bizarre circumstance.”
我想了，“这实在太奇特了”
Then I started looking at myself in the mirror,
我就开始照镜子看着自己
and I couldn’t recognize, who I was.
也无法辨认我到底是谁
And I thought, “This is extra-bizarre. Trés bizarre!”
我想了，“这实在是太奇怪了”
A psychoanalyst will say, “Yes, with the onset of puberty,
心理学家可能会解释说，“是的
if the adolescent youth becomes very …”, whatever.
青春期的少年都会这样...”
Like, when my brother, the urologist, was in med school,
就像我哥，当时读高中
he had this girlfriend …
带了女朋友来
And, who I was, sort of, if you want to say,
我当时某种程度上讲也在传道
preaching to, but talking to about philosophical things.
讲一些哲学性的话题
And she was confiding in me that she was asking herself,
她向我吐露说
“Who am I? Where’ve I come from?”,
“我是谁，我从哪里来”这种问题
What comes under the heading of self-determination
这在黑格尔的哲学里叫
in Hegelian language.
自我决定
So I thought she was really cool person.
我觉得她很酷
Because I thought, “Oh, this is somebody I can relate to.
因为我觉得我可以跟她建立联系
She has self-doubts.”
她会自我疑问
And when I brought it up to my brother,
当我跟我哥提起
he said, “Oh, she is just going through a phase.
他说，“哦，她只不过正经历这个阶段
She’ll get over that.”
很快就会过去的。”
And I thought, “Means she’s going to get over
我想了“是说她将不再
inquiring who she is, trying to understand, who she is,
询问她是谁，想搞清楚自己
where she’s come from, what her purpose is …”
从哪里来，目的是什么了吗..."
I was shocked. I thought,
我很震惊，想了
“No, she shouldn’t get over that.”
"不，不应该就这么过去了。”
Human form of life is very rarely achieved.
人类的生命形式是很难很宝贵才能获得
Like other life forms, it’s temporary.
像其他的生命一样也是短暂的
All the different life forms are temporary.
所有不同的生命形式都是暂时的
But in this one there’s …
但在人类时
fortunate souls may get that chance of association
幸运的灵魂能有机会与圣人联谊
and engage in Kṛṣṇa culture.
致力于奎师那文化